NERIJA BALAN

UX Designer

INFO

Phone

+45 42 67 10 72



Email

nerija.balan@gmail.com



website

nerijabalan.com

EDUCATION

BA Digital Concept Development

KEA

Copenhagen / Denmark 2016 - 2017

AP Multimedia Design and Comunication

KEA

Copenhagen / Denmark 2014 - 2016

BA History

Vytautas Magnus University Kaunas / Lithuania 2008 - 2012

LANGUAGES

English - proficient

Danish - intermediate

Lithuanian - native

PROFILE

I am a UX designer with experience in researching and developing solutions that meet both users' needs and business goals. I have more than 3 years of working experience with development and implamentation of product and web design.

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer - Nordija January 2017 - ongoing

As a UX designer I organize user research that provides the basis for a new IPTV solution. The solution improves overall navigation and the content discovery process for end-users. The solution is designed to fit multiple platforms with specific focus on iOS and Android devices.

Graphic Designer - Evision Inovation ApSJanuary 2016 - 2017 January

I worked as a graphic designer on a project basis. I have created logo designs for the company's products and visual elements for print and web. The graphic material was used to improve overall comunication with the clients and bussines partners.

UX and UI Designer - Freesoft ApS August 2015 - November 2015

During my internship I have solved various design-related tasks. I carried out user research that I used to map out a new user journey. This led to overall improvments in the user interface of the company's products (KidsMonitor SFO apps for parents and teachers).

DESIGNER'S TOOLBOX

Adobe Photoshop

UX & UI design Adobe Indesign
User Testing Adobe After Effects

Flinto HTML 5
Sketch CSS 3
Adobe Illustrator WordPress